<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Studio Children&#039;s Health Defense</title>
	<atom:link href="https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org</link>
	<description>Help Children&#039;s Health Defense</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 13:42:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Studio_logo01.png</url>
	<title>Studio Children&#039;s Health Defense</title>
	<link>https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Children&#8217;s Medical Center Dallas Ranked Best Children&#8217;s Hospital in North Texas and Nationally Ranked in 10 Specialties by U.S. News &#038; World Report</title>
		<link>https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/childrens-medical-center-dallas-ranked-best-childrens-hospital-in-north-texas-and-nationally-ranked-in-10-specialties-by-u-s-news-world-report/</link>
					<comments>https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/childrens-medical-center-dallas-ranked-best-childrens-hospital-in-north-texas-and-nationally-ranked-in-10-specialties-by-u-s-news-world-report/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 13:42:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/?p=34</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DALLAS, June 21, 2023 /PRNewswire/ &#8212; Children&#8217;s Health is proud to announce that Children&#8217;s Medical Center Dallas has again been recognized among the nation&#8217;s best pediatric hospitals by U.S. News &#38; World Report for 2023-2024. Children&#8217;s Medical Center Dallas continues to be the only hospital in North Texas and one of only a select few [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>DALLAS, June 21, 2023 /PRNewswire/ &#8212; Children&#8217;s Health is proud to announce that Children&#8217;s Medical Center Dallas has again been recognized among the nation&#8217;s best pediatric hospitals by U.S. News &amp; World Report for 2023-2024. Children&#8217;s Medical Center Dallas continues to be the only hospital in North Texas and one of only a select few in the nation to be ranked in all 10 pediatric specialties in the U.S. News &amp; World Report&#8217;s annual Best Children&#8217;s Hospitals report. This marks the sixth consecutive year and the 12th time since 2008 that Children&#8217;s Medical Center Dallas has been recognized as one of the top pediatric hospitals in the nation across all 10 specialties.</p>
<p>&#8220;Once again, being recognized as a national leader in pediatric health care by U.S. News &amp; World Report is a tribute to our Children&#8217;s Health team members and academic physician partners at UT Southwestern Medical Center, all who share an unwavering commitment to make life better for children,&#8221; said Christopher J. Durovich, president and chief executive officer at Children&#8217;s Health. &#8220;We are especially proud of being one of only 22 children&#8217;s hospitals out of the nearly 200 surveyed who ranked in all 10 specialties and the only one in North Texas to do so. The recognition underscores Children&#8217;s Medical Center Dallas&#8217; dedication to advancing pediatric health care and improving the lives of children and families in our community.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;UT Southwestern and Children&#8217;s Health share a commitment to innovation and teamwork, which is reflected in the exceptional care and service provided to pediatric patients and their families by our physicians and advanced practice providers working alongside the entire team at Children&#8217;s Health,&#8221; said Dr. Daniel K. Podolsky, president of UT Southwestern Medical Center. &#8220;We continue to work together to find new ways to expand access and best meet the needs of our community.&#8221;</p>
<p>U.S. News &amp; World Report&#8217;s annual rankings of children&#8217;s hospitals are widely regarded as a comprehensive and reliable assessment, employing a multifaceted approach that encompasses crucial factors such as clinical expertise, patient outcomes and hospital structure. The rankings also incorporate national reputation, measured by a survey of thousands of pediatric specialists providing their expert opinions on the health systems they consider best equipped to handle the most critically ill children, regardless of location or financial considerations.</p>
<p><strong>The 10 pediatric specialties and Children&#8217;s Medical Center Dallas&#8217; national rankings in each area are as follows:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Cancer: No. 15</li>
<li>Cardiology &amp; Heart Surgery: No. 35</li>
<li>Diabetes &amp; Endocrinology: No.14</li>
<li>Gastroenterology &amp; GI Surgery: No. 15</li>
<li>Neonatology: No. 36</li>
<li>Nephrology: No.16</li>
<li>Neurology &amp; Neurosurgery: No.15</li>
<li>Orthopedics: No. 4*</li>
<li>Pulmonology &amp; Lung Surgery: No. 22</li>
<li>Urology: No. 15</li>
</ul>
<p>*U.S. News includes Scottish Rite for Children in its evaluation of the performance of Children&#8217;s Medical Center Dallas for Pediatric Orthopedics.</p>
<p><strong>Children&#8217;s Health U.S. News &amp; World Report&#8217;s Highlights</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>6th year in a row ranked 10 out of 10</li>
<li>Best children&#8217;s hospital in North Texas</li>
<li>Ranked #2 in the Southwest</li>
<li>Ranked #16 nationally</li>
<li>Only pediatric system ranked 10 out of 10 in North Texas</li>
<li>12th year to be nationally ranked 10 out of 10 by USNWR</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>About U.S. News ranking methodology</strong></p>
<p>To create the pediatric rankings, U.S. News &amp; World Report gathers key clinical data from nearly 200 medical centers through a detailed survey that evaluates measures such as patient safety, infection prevention and adequacy of nurse staffing. Part of each hospital&#8217;s score is also derived from surveys of more than 15,000 pediatric specialists who are asked where they would send the sickest children in their specialty. RTI International, an independent research and consulting firm, then analyzes the data and ranks the top 50 children&#8217;s hospitals in each of the 10 pediatric specialty areas. In 2023, only 88 children&#8217;s hospitals were ranked in at least one of the 10 pediatric specialties evaluated by U.S. News &amp; World Report.</p>
<p><strong>About Children&#8217;s Health℠</strong></p>
<p>Children&#8217;s Health℠ is the leading pediatric health care system in North Texas and has long been recognized as a leader in pediatric health. Children&#8217;s Health campuses include Children&#8217;s Medical Center Dallas, Children&#8217;s Medical Center Plano and multiple Children&#8217;s Health Specialty Centers. With its academic partner, UT Southwestern, Children&#8217;s Medical Center Dallas is consistently ranked #1 children&#8217;s hospital in North Texas and among the nation&#8217;s best pediatric hospitals by U.S. News &amp; World Report. Its commitment to excellence and providing outstanding care across all aspects of pediatrics has resulted in 10 out of 10 specialty programs being ranked among the best for six consecutive years, including Cancer, Cardiology &amp; Heart Surgery, Diabetes &amp; Endocrinology, Gastroenterology &amp; GI Surgery, Neonatology, Nephrology, Neurology &amp; Neurosurgery, Orthopedics, Pulmonology and Urology.</p>
<p>In addition, Children&#8217;s Health nurses have received the Magnet® designation for the past 13 years, the highest honor for nursing excellence, and it has been named one of the 150 Best Places to Work in Healthcare by Becker&#8217;s Hospital Review for 10 consecutive years.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/childrens-medical-center-dallas-ranked-best-childrens-hospital-in-north-texas-and-nationally-ranked-in-10-specialties-by-u-s-news-world-report/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>1.5 million people dropped from Medicaid as states begin post-pandemic purge</title>
		<link>https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/1-5-million-people-dropped-from-medicaid-as-states-begin-post-pandemic-purge/</link>
					<comments>https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/1-5-million-people-dropped-from-medicaid-as-states-begin-post-pandemic-purge/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 13:39:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/?p=31</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[More than 1 million people have been dropped from Medicaid in the past couple of months as some states moved swiftly to halt health care coverage following the end of the coronavirus pandemic. Most got dropped for not filling out paperwork. Though the eligibility review is required by the federal government, President’s Joe Biden’s administration [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>More than 1 million people have been dropped from Medicaid in the past couple of months as some states moved swiftly to halt health care coverage following the end of the coronavirus pandemic.</p>
<p>Most got dropped for not filling out paperwork.</p>
<p>Though the eligibility review is required by the federal government, President’s Joe Biden’s administration isn’t too pleased at how efficiently some other states are accomplishing the task.</p>
<p>“Pushing through things and rushing it will lead to eligible people — kids and families — losing coverage for some period of time,” Daniel Tsai, a top federal Medicaid official, recently told reporters.</p>
<p>Already, about 1.5 million people have been removed from Medicaid in more than two dozen states that started the process in April or May, according to publicly available reports and data obtained by The Associated Press.</p>
<p>Florida has dropped several hundred thousand people, by far the most among states. The drop rate also has been particularly high in other states. For people whose cases were decided in May, around half or more got dropped in Arkansas, Idaho, Kansas, Nevada, New Hampshire, Oklahoma, South Dakota, Utah and West Virginia.</p>
<p>By its own count, Arkansas has dropped more than 140,000 people from Medicaid.</p>
<p>The eligibility redeterminations have created headaches for Jennifer Mojica, 28, who was told in April that she no longer qualified for Medicaid because Arkansas had incorrectly determined her income was above the limit.</p>
<p>She got that resolved, but was then told her 5-year-old son was being dropped from Medicaid because she had requested his cancellation — something that never happened, she said. Her son’s coverage has been restored, but now Mojica says she’s been told her husband no longer qualifies. The uncertainty has been frustrating, she said.</p>
<p>Arkansas officials said they have tried to renew coverage automatically for as many people as possible and placed a special emphasis on reaching families with children. But a 2021 state law requires the post-pandemic eligibility redeterminations to be completed in six months, and the state will continue “to swiftly disenroll individuals who are no longer eligible,” the Department of Human Services said in statement.</p>
<p>Arkansas Gov. Sarah Huckabee Sanders has dismissed criticism of the state’s process.</p>
<p>“Those who do not qualify for Medicaid are taking resources from those who need them,” Sanders said on Twitter last month. “But the pandemic is over — and we are leading the way back to normalcy.”</p>
<p>More than 93 million people nationwide were enrolled in Medicaid as of the most recent available data in February — up nearly one-third from the pre-pandemic total in January 2020. The rolls swelled because federal law prohibited states from removing people from Medicaid during the health emergency in exchange for providing states with increased funding.</p>
<p>Now that eligibility reviews have resumed, states have begun plowing through a backlog of cases to determine whether people’s income or life circumstances have changed. States have a year to complete the process. But tracking down responses from everyone has proved difficult, because some people have moved, changed contact information or disregarded mailings about the renewal process.</p>
<p>Advocates fear that many households losing coverage may include children who are actually still eligible, because Medicaid covers children at higher income levels than their parents or guardians. A report last year by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services forecast that children would be disproportionately impacted, with more than half of those disenrolled still actually eligible.</p>
<p>That’s difficult to confirm, however, because the federal Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services doesn’t require states to report a demographic breakdown of those dropped.</p>
<p>Medicaid recipients in numerous states have described the eligibility redetermination process as frustrating.</p>
<p>Julie Talamo, of Port Richey, Florida, said she called state officials every day for weeks, spending hours on hold, when she was trying to ensure her 19-year-old special-needs son, Thomas, was going to stay on Medicaid.</p>
<p>She knew her own coverage would end but was shocked to hear Thomas’ coverage would be whittled down to a different program that could force her family to pay $2,000 per month. Eventually, an activist put Talamo in contact with a senior state health care official who confirmed her son would stay on Medicaid.</p>
<p>“This system was designed to fail people,” Talamo said of the haphazard process.</p>
<p>In Indiana, Samantha Richards, 35, said she has been on Medicaid her whole life and currently works two part-time jobs as a custodian. Richards recalled receiving a letter earlier this year indicating that the pandemic-era Medicaid protection was ending. She said a local advocacy group helped her navigate the renewal process. But she remains uneasy.</p>
<p>“Medicaid can be a little unpredictable,” Richards said. “There is still that concern that just out of nowhere, I will either get a letter saying that we have to reapply because we missed some paperwork, or I missed a deadline, or I’m going to show up at the doctor’s office or the pharmacy and they’re going to say, ‘Your insurance didn’t go through.’”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/1-5-million-people-dropped-from-medicaid-as-states-begin-post-pandemic-purge/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Children’s Health ranked top kids hospital in DFW</title>
		<link>https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/childrens-health-ranked-top-kids-hospital-in-dfw/</link>
					<comments>https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/childrens-health-ranked-top-kids-hospital-in-dfw/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 13:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/?p=28</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Children’s Medical Center Dallas continues to be the only pediatric system in North Texas ranked in all 10 pediatric specialties in the U.S. News &#38; World Report’s annual Best Children’s Hospitals report for the sixth consecutive year. &#8220;It means we absolutely believe in our mission of being the best in what we do, taking care [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Children’s Medical Center Dallas continues to be the only pediatric system in North Texas ranked in all 10 pediatric specialties in the U.S. News &amp; World Report’s annual Best Children’s Hospitals report for the sixth consecutive year.</p>
<p>&#8220;It means we absolutely believe in our mission of being the best in what we do, taking care of patients in the area and the region,&#8221; says Dr. Dai Chung, chief medical officer for the Joint Pediatric Enterprise between Children’s Health and UT Southwestern. &#8220;It&#8217;s an incredible feat.&#8221;</p>
<p>Children&#8217;s Medical Center Dallas is nationally ranked in all 10 pediatric specialties that US News ranked. That includes a #4 ranking in Pediatric Orthopedics.</p>
<p>KRLD&#8217;s John Liddle talked with Dr. Dai Chung, and Lindsay King and Kevin Richardson, the parents of Merce Richardson, whom Dr. Chung operated on to correct severe gastrointestinal issues two years ago.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/childrens-health-ranked-top-kids-hospital-in-dfw/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hassenfeld Children&#8217;s Hospital at NYU Langone: A leader in pediatric cardiology and heart surgery care</title>
		<link>https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/hassenfeld-childrens-hospital-at-nyu-langone-a-leader-in-pediatric-cardiology-and-heart-surgery-care/</link>
					<comments>https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/hassenfeld-childrens-hospital-at-nyu-langone-a-leader-in-pediatric-cardiology-and-heart-surgery-care/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 13:36:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/?p=25</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hassenfeld Children&#8217;s Hospital at NYU Langone is the highest ranked in New York for pediatric cardiology and heart surgery care, based on the national specialty ranking in the U.S. News &#38; World Report&#8217;s annual &#8220;Best Children&#8217;s Hospitals&#8221; guide released this week. This ranking signifies the trust our patients and their families place in us when [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hassenfeld Children&#8217;s Hospital at NYU Langone is the highest ranked in New York for pediatric cardiology and heart surgery care, based on the national specialty ranking in the U.S. News &amp; World Report&#8217;s annual &#8220;Best Children&#8217;s Hospitals&#8221; guide released this week.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>This ranking signifies the trust our patients and their families place in us when they choose Hassenfeld Children&#8217;s Hospital for heart disease treatment. We are immensely proud to be recognized, validating our commitment to deliver high-quality, family-centered care to those who need us most.&#8221;</strong></p>
<p><strong>Frank Cecchin, MD, Director of the Division of Pediatric Cardiology and the Andrall E. Pearson Professor of Pediatric Cardiology in the Department of Pediatrics</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>U.S. News &amp; World Report recognized Hassenfeld Children&#8217;s Hospital among the top 15 children&#8217;s hospitals in the nation for children&#8217;s cardiology and heart surgery, which is a huge milestone since opening the doors in 2018, providing a state-of-the art arena to deliver exceptional care.</p>
<p>&#8220;There is nothing more gratifying than to see how well children are doing after a major heart procedure, whether it&#8217;s a month or many years later,&#8221; said Ralph S. Mosca, MD, MBA, the Henry H. Arnhold Chair of Cardiothoracic Surgery and chief of the Division of Pediatric and Adult Congenital Cardiac Surgery at NYU Langone. &#8220;These successful outcomes are why Hassenfeld Children&#8217;s Hospital is a recognized leader in the multidisciplinary care of pediatric heart conditions.&#8221;</p>
<p>Collaborative and exceptional care for children with the most complex cardiac needs<br />
Hassenfeld Children&#8217;s Hospital&#8217;s cardiologists, congenital heart surgeons, cardiothoracic surgeons, anesthesiologists, cardiac intensivists, cardiac nurse practitioners, and nurses are renowned leaders in the field and work together to treat children with some of the rarest and most complex heart cases from the fetal period through adulthood.</p>
<p>In March 2021, Hassenfeld Children&#8217;s Hospital opened a comprehensive Congenital Heart Center designed to serve the medical and surgical needs of a growing population of patients with congenital heart disease. The 5,500-square-foot space includes outpatient care, diagnostic testing, presurgical and postsurgical procedure appointments, and patient and family education.</p>
<p>Congenital heart surgery at Hassenfeld Children&#8217;s Hospital is a national leader performing nearly 250 operations annually on the full spectrum of pediatric and adult congenital heart disease including transplantation. The program has the best risk adjusted survival rate of any hospital program in New York State for pediatric patients and among the very best in the nation, according the latest data from the Congenital Heart Surgery data base (CHSD) maintained by the Society for Thoracic Surgery and a report from the NYS Department of Health.</p>
<p>A collaboration between the Pediatric Congenital Heart Program and adult programs, the Congenital Heart Transition Program teaches adolescents to take charge of the own cardiac care and connects them with experts in the Adult Congenital Heart Disease Program at NYU Langone, which is accredited by the Adult Congenital Heart Association as an Adult Congenital Heart Disease Comprehensive Care Center, the first in New York State.</p>
<p>In partnership with the frontline providers, support services including child life, creative arts therapies, integrative behavioral health, nutrition, social work, and spiritual support also play a role in the extraordinary care patients receive, thanks to Sala Institute for Child and Family Centered Care, part of Hassenfeld Children&#8217;s Hospital.</p>
<p>&#8220;Since Hassenfeld Children&#8217;s Hospital&#8217;s inception, we have become a place that our patients and families can come for care, answers, and hope, and we have the great privilege of delivering it,&#8221; said Catherine S. Manno, MD, the Pat and John Rosenwald Professor of Pediatrics and chair of the Department of Pediatrics. &#8220;I am grateful for all the faculty and employees whose continued commitment to delivering exceptional and empathetic care has made this ranking possible.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/hassenfeld-childrens-hospital-at-nyu-langone-a-leader-in-pediatric-cardiology-and-heart-surgery-care/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Missouri lags behind most states in children’s health, report finds</title>
		<link>https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/missouri-lags-behind-most-states-in-childrens-health-report-finds/</link>
					<comments>https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/missouri-lags-behind-most-states-in-childrens-health-report-finds/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 13:35:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/?p=22</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Missouri ranks in the bottom third of all states for children’s health, according to a recent report using data from 2021. The annual Kids Count Data Book from the Annie E. Casey Foundation, released this month, evaluates states on four metrics of child well-being. Those are: health, economic well-being, education and family &#38; community. For [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Missouri ranks in the bottom third of all states for children’s health, according to a recent report using data from 2021.</p>
<p>The annual Kids Count Data Book from the Annie E. Casey Foundation, released this month, evaluates states on four metrics of child well-being. Those are: health, economic well-being, education and family &amp; community.</p>
<p>For overall child well-being, Missouri ranks near the middle: 28th of 50 states, with 50 being the worst. Other Midwestern states, Minnesota, Iowa, Nebraska and Wisconsin, were in the top ten of all states for child well-being.</p>
<p>Bringing down the state’s overall ranking was one factor in particular: children’s health.</p>
<p>Only 15 states in the country had a lower rating for children’s health.</p>
<p>“Our health rankings are part of the problem,” said Tracy Greever-Rice, program director of Missouri KIDS COUNT.</p>
<p>“We have work to do here in Missouri around infant mortality,” Greever-Rice said. “And we also have work to do, like many states with large rural populations, in terms of teen and adolescent deaths.”</p>
<p>Only 10 other states had the same or worse rates of child and teen deaths as Missouri, one of the factors included in the health measure.</p>
<p>The rate of child and teen deaths was 39 per 100,000 in Missouri in 2021 — up from 32 per 100,000 just two years earlier. The state’s trend mirrored the national trend, which increased from 25 deaths per 100,000 to 30 deaths per 100,000 from 2019 to 2021</p>
<p>Greever-Rice said several factors could have contributed to the state’s relatively high rate of child and teen deaths in 2021.</p>
<p>“Particularly at risk — and a change that we’ve seen over the past few years — are adolescent boys in more rural areas,” Greever-Rice said, “and of course, Missouri, like everywhere else has been impacted by the opioid and fentanyl epidemic.</p>
<p>“So we just have some high risk populations here that we have work to do around.”</p>
<p>Suicide rates among young people have increased nationally over the last several decades, particularly in rural areas, where mental health services can be scarcer, research has found.</p>
<p>Firearms became the leading cause of kids’ deaths in the United States in 2020, surpassing car accidents. According to Children’s Defense Fund, Missouri was one of ten states that accounted for half of all child and teen gun deaths in the nation from 2011-2020. Bills to limit access to guns failed in the legislature this session.</p>
<p>Other indicators of children’s health — the rates of low birth-weight babies, children without health insurance, and children who are overweight or obese — were all slightly worse in Missouri than on average, according to the report.</p>
<p>The best states for children’s health, according to the report, include Massachusetts, Vermont and New Hampshire, while the worst are Texas, Louisiana and Mississippi.</p>
<p>Missouri children fared best, out of the four broad indicators of well-being, on the measure of economic well-being. The state ranked 18th of 50 on economic well-being.</p>
<p>While 3 in 10 children nationally live in households with a high housing cost burden, only around 2 in 10 Missouri children do, per the report.</p>
<p>The rate of kids whose parents lack secure employment is also slightly better in Missouri at 26% than nationally, 29%.</p>
<p>The rate of children in poverty roughly mirrors the national average — 16% in Missouri and 17% nationally. The rate of teens not in school and not working is 7% in Missouri, equal to the national average.</p>
<p>The Kids Count index also included data on the cost of child care nationally, though it did not factor into the overall well-being rating.</p>
<p>“For many, many families right now,” Greever-Rice said, “the cost [of child care] continues to go up and availability just decreases, particularly in rural areas and underserved areas.”</p>
<p>In Missouri, a single parent with a toddler attending a child care center would pay 28% of the median income on child care, according to the Kids Count report. Dozens of interviews conducted by The Independent and Muckrock indicated that that burden can be untenable for many families — even though it is actually a lower burden than in much of the rest of the country, per the report.</p>
<p>As the Missouri Independent and Muckrock’s investigative collaboration, Disappearing Daycare, found, the child care crisis is one not just of cost but access: Missourians struggle to find child care openings, particularly for infants, and the situation is even worse for those seeking government assistance.</p>
<p>The average cost for a toddler’s care at a center in Missouri was nearly $9,000, according to KIDS COUNT.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/missouri-lags-behind-most-states-in-childrens-health-report-finds/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spare change to positive change, Children’s Health Foundation launches new rewards program</title>
		<link>https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/spare-change-to-positive-change-childrens-health-foundation-launches-new-rewards-program/</link>
					<comments>https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/spare-change-to-positive-change-childrens-health-foundation-launches-new-rewards-program/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 13:34:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/?p=18</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kids face a number of challenges when battling serious health issues, but the Children’s Health Foundation is looking to “ChangeIt.” In collaboration with Ascend Fundraising Solutions, the new rewards network platform allows users to give back to those in need. By signing their credit cards up for the online program, users are able to round [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kids face a number of challenges when battling serious health issues, but the Children’s Health Foundation is looking to “ChangeIt.”</p>
<p>In collaboration with Ascend Fundraising Solutions, the new rewards network platform allows users to give back to those in need.</p>
<p>By signing their credit cards up for the online program, users are able to round up each purchase to the nearest dollar, turning spare change into positive change.</p>
<p>“We couldn’t do what we do in making kids feel comfortable and making them feel like it’s (the hospital) maybe not such a scary place without donors in our community,” said Jennifer Baxter, director of community relations and the Children’s Miracle Network.</p>
<p>She added that the funds donated will go towards programs and services at both TVCC, formerly Thames Valley Children’s Centre, and the Children’s Hospital.</p>
<p>“Things like our therapeutic clown, child-life specialists, art therapists, Kids in the Block opportunities at TVCC, as well as the Opportunities to Participate program,” Baxter said. “It’s things like that (which) are not covered by government funding – they are covered by donors like our community.”</p>
<p>Kim Woodbridge is an account manager with Ascend Fundraising Solutions and highlights that the rewards program is a win-win for everyone.</p>
<p>“I know everyone knows of the incredible impact that Children’s Health Foundation has in our community. So, this is a really easy way to be a part of that and give back,” she said. “At the same time, by becoming a part of the ChangeIt program, you have access to some exclusive benefits, rewards and cashback offers on the purchases that you’re making at both local and national businesses.”</p>
<p>Users also receive a tax receipt for their donations to “acknowledge and encourage their generosity,” according to the foundation.</p>
<p>The Children’s Health Foundation and Children’s Hospital see roughly 66,000 families every year, with the TVCC seeing around 11,000 kids annually both across western Ontario, from Windsor to London, Kitchener-Waterloo, Thunder Bay, and remote communities.</p>
<p>Woodbridge said that the program kicks off at a free launch event at Storybook Gardens Friday evening.</p>
<p>“We’re encouraging families to come down and have some playtime in the park and learn and even sign up for the ChangeIt program,” she said. “We’re also going to have the children’s band, The Thinking Caps there, the waterpark is going to be open, the concessions are open, and it’s all just surrounding the program which is so important.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/spare-change-to-positive-change-childrens-health-foundation-launches-new-rewards-program/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The US anti-vax group Children&#8217;s Health Defense&#8217;s expansion to Europe</title>
		<link>https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/the-us-anti-vax-group-childrens-health-defenses-expansion-to-europe/</link>
					<comments>https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/the-us-anti-vax-group-childrens-health-defenses-expansion-to-europe/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 13:32:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/?p=14</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By Roman Adamczyk, External OSINT Investigator, EU DisinfoLab, and Alexandre Alaphilippe, Executive Director, EU DisinfoLab On February 1, the EDMO Belux project published an investigation titled “The US anti-vax group Children’s Health Defense’s expansion to Europe”. This investigation analyses Robert Kennedy Jr’s anti-vax movement Children’s Health Defense efforts to expand its activities in Europe. Since [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Roman Adamczyk, External OSINT Investigator, EU DisinfoLab, and Alexandre Alaphilippe, Executive Director, EU DisinfoLab</p>
<p>On February 1, the EDMO Belux project published an investigation titled “The US anti-vax group Children’s Health Defense’s expansion to Europe”.</p>
<p>This investigation analyses Robert Kennedy Jr’s anti-vax movement Children’s Health Defense efforts to expand its activities in Europe. Since August 2020, the US anti-vaccine group has created a legal structure in Belgium and organised multiple events to spread its narratives and build a network of like-minded anti-vax organisations.</p>
<p>The group has developed its lobbying efforts targeting the European Parliament, building up relationships with specific MEPs without being registered in the EU transparency register at the time of the study. It also organised two press conferences at the Brussels Press Club.</p>
<p>Even though the impact of Children’s Health Defense seems to remain limited in Europe for now, especially online, it seems likely that the US group will try to continue to expand its presence in the EU 27 Member States by developing its offline lobbying efforts in Brussels and contributing to the growth of the European anti-vaccine informational ecosystems.</p>
<p>Moreover, social media platforms’ efforts to circumscribe the reach of Children’s Health Defense have been limited so far, and the EU remains vulnerable to the influence activities of many questionable actors like US anti-vaxxers.</p>
<p>The study raises an important question as to what should be done to limit the opportunities for anti-vax groups to manipulate public discussions around vaccines in the EU and prevent them from contributing to the creation of new health crises, putting at risk the health of entire communities.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://studio.childrenshealthdefense.org/the-us-anti-vax-group-childrens-health-defenses-expansion-to-europe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
